Paul Plant

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/paul-plant

Email: mail@paulplant.com

About Me

I am a software engineer with years of experience in a variety of areas. I've built cloud services, robotics control servers, and firmware for mobile devices. I raise the bar by digging into hard problems, learning something new, and developing it into something useful for my clients. I am a Canadian citizen eligible for TN Visa: Engineer without sponsorship.

Skills

C, C++, Typescript, Python

Amazon Web Services (AWS), distributed systems, microservices, linux programming, parallel and concurrent programming, basic electronics

Experience

Amazon Web Services — Software Development Engineer

November 2019 - present, aws.amazon.com

I work on native AWS (100% cloud based) services in TypeScript and Java, and create deployment pipelines and infrastructure in CDK. I have done substantial work spearheading the adoption of CDK in my team and have implemented a framework to streamline the creation of new CDK pipelines and support best practices, like isolated developer deployments. I was a contributor to the launch of Amazon Connect Real Time Contact Lens, where I worked across teams to implement the API connecting the UI to the backend. I have done substantial work validating a custom Redis based throttling solution our team developed, diagnosed why the solution did not work as intended, and implemented a new client for us to use as a replacement. And other misc. ops, customer support, ops tools, and region launches.

Polaris Motion — Software Developer

June 2016 - September 2017, pmdi.com

I worked in C and C++ on the server for their CNC control device. I lead a major refactoring of the code base to support new hardware platforms. I designed and implemented the software for a high speed spindle controller prototype for a client. I developed a custom framework for clients to implement their own monitoring logic using callbacks in C. And other misc. customer support, technical writing.

Netgear Canada — Software Developer Coop

January 2015 - December 2015, netgear.com

I wrote firmware in C for Aircard mobile hotspot devices and performed basic electronics troubleshooting. I performed troubleshooting on batteries from various suppliers and implemented support for them into the Aircard firmware. I wrote scripts to automate battery tests, monitor battery charge cycles, and produce reports for review. I implemented a bootloader patch to fix dead battery charging on devices which did not support it in hardware. And other misc. work.

Education

University of Victoria — Bachelor of Science in Computer Science September 2017 - August 2019, Victoria BC www.uvic.ca Graduated with distinction

BCIT — Diploma in Electrical & Computer Engineering Technology September 2013 - May 2016, Burnaby BC www.bcit.ca